Caitlyn!
Hey.
Sorry, I don’t think Kara wants to talk to you.
Her name is Caitlyn.
And who are you, exactly?
Jeremy.
Her ex-fiancé.
[ARIEL] Mom! Jeremy’s here. Kara’s ex!
I’ll take care of it. You guys stay here.
Kara’s real name is Caitlyn?
How can you not know, Sir Han?
Kara always talks about that, even to our guests!
Actually, all of our guests.
[PEARL] How she changed her name to
Kara because “karajaw” means “awesome”.
So, that’s Jeremy?
Why is he here? Is he looking for me?
Whoever you may be...
[CAROL] Kara deserves to be happy.
[JAO] You don’t have to say anything.
I just want you to know that I’m here.
He made me feel like...
I was his whole world.
Even though he kept cheating on me.
I don’t know why I let that happen to me.
You have to forgive yourself.
[JAO] Don’t feel guilty for wanting to be loved.
Because you found it.
You found you.
You found it on this island.
I’m hard to love, Jao.
I’m ready to love you, Kara.
Do you want to know what I told Ruth?
That I'm ready to love you
no matter what.
That’s why I’m here.
[JAO SNIFFS]
[KARA AND JAO CRYING SOFTLY]
Sir Han, why are you being so nice to me?
I think I forgot something.
- [HAN BIN CLEARS THROAT] - Sir Han!
Why are you being so nice to me?
Okay.
[HAN BIN SPEAKS KOREAN] I’m in love with you, Pearl.
I have been in love with you for the longest time.
And it pains my heart that I can’t tell you.
How much you make me happy,
how you make me smile every day.
How you make me want to celebrate life...
whenever you’re around.
I love you...
but I can’t love you.
Because I’m not who you think I am.
Ah... That's...
That’s so unfair!
I didn’t understand anything.
It’s nothing, Pearl.
I’m just saying that…
I love your energy.
It’s infectious!
You’re one of the most authentic humans I’ve ever met.
It’s like you have a...
pure soul.
Okay, then.
But it sounded like you said something much longer.
No, that’s really it, Pearl.
Let’s just drop the subject.
Okay.
[PEARL TAKES A DEEP BREATH]
[ALON BY JL]
[FOOD SIZZLING]
[JAO] Pining, is that going to be a while?
Pining already has your order memorized, Sir Handsome.
You’ve been here a long time, huh?
[SIARGAONON] Are you planning to stay here, sir?
Yeah, I’ve been thinking about it.
I think I might stay here for good.
There it is!
The curse got you, too!
- [JAO LAUGHS] - You just don’t want to miss Kara.
[JAO CLEARS THROAT]
- Oh, thank you, Pining. - Thank you.
I guess so.
I really fell hard for Kara.
Wow. Is that so?
That’s how bad you’ve got it?
I guess.
All I know is...
that I’m willing to do anything for her.
To make her happy,
to make her feel secure.
It’s a good thing I can work remotely now.
So I can be with her. That won’t be a problem for us.
Hungry?
[TANTAN] Starving. I’m exhausted.
Cheers.
It’s the hunger talking.
Pining, you never disappoint.
- [HAN BIN] Pearl. - [PEARL] Sir.
Here’s your recommendation letter and work experience letter.
Are you all set with your requirements?
Yes, Sir Han.
I will just get my transcript notarized
so I can submit them to the school.
How’s your motivation letter?
Oh, I’m finished already.
Um...
- Want to hear it? - [HAN BIN] Go ahead.
[PEARL] Okay.
[PEARL SIGHS] I’m nervous!
[PEARL CLEARS THROAT]
Dear Admissions Committee…
I’m writing to express my interest
in the Tourism and Hotel Management scholarship at your university.
Growing up in Siargao,
I’ve always been surrounded by the beauty of our island.
Yet, I’ve always dreamed of seeing the world beyond it.
My father...
My father left the Philippines when I was a child
to pursue opportunities abroad.
Even though he never came back,
I never resented him.
In fact,
his choice inspired me to chase my own dreams.
Studying at your university would help me learn
and gain the skills and knowledge
that adhere to international hospitality standards.
This scholarship is not just an opportunity to study.
It's a chance for me to grow...
learn…
and to honor the people who supported me.
It’s time for this island girl to grow into someone who can serve others
at a world-class level.
It’s time for this island girl
to leave the familiar behind
and become her best self.
Thank you for considering my application.
Sincerely, Pearl.
Is that good, Sir Han?
Um…
[PEARL LAUGHS] Sorry.
Very good nice.
- Very good nice? - Yeah, I’ll go ahead.
[HAN BIN SNIFFLING]
- [KARA] Morning, Noah. - Morning.
Kara, thanks for helping
with the site documentation and budget proposal.
That was a huge help to be able to process the permits for the mangrove project.
[KARA] No problem.
I’m just happy that everything is ready on our end.
[NOAH] Right.
But while we're waiting for the LGU’s approval,
there’s something I’d like to discuss with you.
Sure! What is it?
[NOAH] Well...
I was recruited by an international NGO.
And they wanted me as legal consultant and policy advisor
for coastal and marine protection.
Wow, congratulations, Noah!
That’s amazing!
[NOAH] Thanks.
It’s a great opportunity.
But it means I’ll have to leave the mangrove project.
Kara,
I’d like you to take over for me.
I know how passionate you are when it comes to mangroves.
I’m confident you can lead this project.
Besides, I'll still be around to help and guide you
before I leave.
Okay. I'll do it.
I’ll let our Denmark headquarters know that you've agreed to take the lead.
Once the permits are approved, we can start building the T-fence.
It's a pretty large area, isn't it?
The damage from Typhoon Odette was extensive.
Yeah. There used to be natural mangroves there, too, right?
Just a few, but they were all destroyed when Typhoon Odette hit.
The area eroded, so nothing grows there anymore.
That's why restoring it is so important.
Well, as soon as we get the permits and the T-fence is in place,
we can start planting.
[NOAH] Thanks, Kara.
I know I can count on you.
We’ll be seeing each other more often, Ruth.
And you’ll have more friends soon.
[JAO] What are you and Ruth keeping from me now?
[KARA CHUCKLES]
Remember Noah’s mangrove project?
Mm-hm.
He wants to assign it to me.
- [JAO] Wow, that’s amazing! - [KARA LAUGHS]
I’m sure you’ll do great, Kara.
- I’m always here for you. - Thank you.
I’m always here to support you.
Thanks.
- Congratulations! - Thank you!
[KARA LAUGHS]
[FOOTSTEPS ON STAIRS]
You know, about the other night…
I just wanted to talk to you because…
I just wanted to check on you.
But I found out that...
you didn’t want to talk to me.
So, I wonder what changed your mind?
I realized this is my chance for closure.
It’s been years, Caitlyn.
I thought we'd settled it legally.
I thought that was in the past.
Do you think I haven’t moved on?
I’m married now.
Why are you being so dramatic?
[KARA SCOFFS]
I never forced you to love me.
What’s going on, Cait?
You know I’ve dreaded this moment my whole life?
I thought I wouldn’t be able to handle it.
I was completely crushed.
But I was so lucky to have recovered from all the shit that you put me through.
I was…
I was so afraid of you.
So afraid of your family because of everything.
After seeing you the other night,
I finally decided that I wanted to move on.
From this.
From you.
You don’t have power over me anymore.
And I finally decided to forgive myself.
Leaving all of that…
[KARA] leaving you…
was the best decision I've ever made.
I’m the life raft.
[KARA VOICEOVER] Life hits you like a wave.
Sometimes the waves just keep coming.
They hit so hard you think you’ll never make it back up
But that’s not true.
Once you realize you can let go of the things that weigh you down,
that’s when you'll see…
That you...
You can be your own life raft.
You can rise above it and be free.
Then you’ll learn to appreciate the waves.
But, sometimes, the waves are so unpredictable.
Before you know it,
a storm is already on its way.
[CAROL] Remember when we first met?
You were completely broken back then.
But now, so many good things are going on for you.
[WAITER] Good evening. I’m sorry, we have a private gathering tonight.
[WAITER] So we are closed.
[FOREIGNER] Seriously? We came all the way here,
now you’re telling us to leave?
Hi there.
Excuse me?
[FOREIGNER] Out of all the Filipinas throwing themselves at me,
you’re lucky!
Hey! Stop!
What is...
Hey!
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
- [CAROL] Hey! Call for help! - [INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
[CAROL] Call the police!
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
[JAO] Kara!
[JAO] I’m here to listen.
What happened back there… brought everything back.
I thought I'd moved on.
I just want you to know that you’re not alone anymore.
[JAO] I’m here now.
I’m not going anywhere.
[JAO] I love you, Kara.